

Maximilian Schaum

Software Engineer Frontend React. JS

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Developer | Founder

Webentwicklung 030 Berlin GmbH

03/2021 - Present

- Optimization of customer Web pages in regard to organic recruitment - increase from 0 - 1 applicants to 10 - 20 applicants per month
- Implementing interfaces to external job boards for automatic transfer of jobs - RESTful API
- · Self-Developed Website Management System for customers
- Online analysis to automatically test webpages for different quality criteria
- CRM Web-Application for recruiting of personnel
- Chrome Extension to automatically scrape data with direct interface to the CRM Application - RESTful API
- Webpage design, creation and SEO optimization React.js

Working Student Web Development

VIPCRUITER GmbH

06/2020 - 03/2021

- Relaunch of multiple webpages of WordPress to Gatsby.js (React.js)
- · Webpage maintenance and optimization

Werkstudent IT / Controlling

Mercedes-Benz AG

09/2019 - 06/2020

- Reporting Dashboard Development
- Excel VBA Programming
- · Process modeling and automation

Working Student Web Development

SCHAUM MASSIVHAUS

05/2017 - 08/2019

- Webpage creation, maintenance and optimization HTML, CSS und JavaScript
- · IT-Administration and accounting

IT-Specialist for software development

IGEPA group GmbH & Co. KG

09/2014 - 04/2017

- JD Edwards E1 Database Programming
- · Java Web Application and Interfaces

- **** 01622715832
- max.schaum4@gmail.com
- https://max-s-resume.netlify.app/
- 12529 Schönefeld, Deutschland

SUMMARY

Reliable and motivated Full-Stack Web
Developer with vast Tech experience.
Specialized in Front-End Development, not afraid
of Back-End. Passionate for creatively finding
solutions to concrete problems with the help of
the Web. Adaptable team player, with the ability
to work independently and the will to go the
extra mile.

SKILLS

React.js Expert Gatsby.js Expert **TailwindCSS** Expert **HTML** Expert Javascript Expert CSS Expert MongoDB Expert **REST API** Advanced Meteor.js Advanced Advanced Node.js Github Actions Advanced Intermediate **Typescript** Next.js Intermediate

LANGUAGES

Deutsch Native Englisch Fluent

EDUCATION

Mathematics / Computer Science

Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin 2021

Bachelors

IT specialist for software development

Oberstufenzentrum Informations- und Medizintechnik

2014

Apprenticeship